<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Money Saving Tips</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details">Tip</string>
    <string name="previous">&lt;&lt;</string>
    <string name="next">&gt;&gt;</string>
    <string name="random">Random Tip</string>
    <string name="action_about">About</string>
    <string name="action_share">Share</string>
    <string name="share_using">Share Using</string>

    <string-array name="tips">
        <item>Shopping list\tAlways go shopping with a prepared list of items to buy. Make sure you stick to the list!</item>
        <item>Don\'t overspend on food\tPrepare your standard \"shopping basked\", compare different stores to find one where you can buy all items the cheapest</item>
        <item>Limit sugar\tLimiting sugar will help both: your budget and your body</item>
        <item>Limit eating out\tTry to limit eating out as much as possible. This will help you to save a lot of money, and you will also quickly find out that preparing food at home can be very enjoyable.\nOne of the biggest money sucking eating out habit is coffee.</item>
        <item>Consider online shopping\tWe all are accustomed to buying electronics online, but recently it\'s becoming more popular to buy grocery online, checkout different online stores and compare their offers, you will save both money and time!</item>
        <item>Browse supplies regularly\tMake sure to browse all your home food supplies regularly to avoid unnecessary past food, this both helps to limit wasted food and will help you save some money. Review your supplies for example weekly and move all items getting close to expiration date to the front of the shelves</item>
        <item>Buy a water filter\tInstead of buying bottled water it\'s worth investing in a water filter and reusable bottle with a built-in carbon filter</item>
        <item>Test cheap food\tDo not believe in the word that \"the brand is better\". Often, the same products are offered under the brand name supermarkets. Read ingredients, check if it\'s the same manufacturer, buy for test and decide yourself whether you satisfy the product for half the price without the logo.</item>
        <item>Change bank account for the one without fees\tBanks change their offer quite frequently, and we should react and change banks. Loyalty in this sector - does not pay.</item>
        <item>Close the unused bank accounts\tIf you have a account bank account that is unnecessary - close them because maybe you limit the possibility to take advantage of the promotion for new customers. Additionally when bank changes their fees, you won\'t be affected</item>
        <item>Use the bonus moneyback\tSome banks support your loyalty - make sure to check your bank offer. Heavy use of the services of the bank (transfer salaries, purchases with debit cards) give you the chance for bonuses of some banks. Earnings depend on the earnings and creativity.</item>
        <item>Repay the loans in other currencies using currency bought online\tInternet Exchange offices have a low spread (the difference between the buying and selling) so that you earn as much as 10 cents on every-selling 1 euro. This will make a lot of difference if you have a lot of loans</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
