<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Money Saving Tips</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details">Tip</string>
    <string name="previous">&lt;&lt;</string>
    <string name="next">&gt;&gt;</string>
    <string name="random">Random Tip</string>
    <string name="action_about">About</string>
    <string name="action_share">Share</string>
    <string name="share_using">Share Using</string>
    <string name="googleAnalytics">UA-54524356-8</string>

    <string-array name="tips">
        <item>Shopping list\tAlways go shopping with a prepared list of items to buy. Make sure you stick to the list!</item>
        <item>Don\'t overspend on food\tPrepare your standard \"shopping basked\", compare different stores to find one where you can buy all items the cheapest</item>
        <item>Limit sugar\tLimiting sugar will help both: your budget and your body</item>
        <item>Limit eating out\tTry to limit eating out as much as possible. This will help you to save a lot of money, and you will also quickly find out that preparing food at home can be very enjoyable.\nOne of the biggest money sucking eating out habit is coffee.</item>
        <item>Consider online shopping\tWe all are accustomed to buying electronics online, but recently it\'s becoming more popular to buy grocery online, checkout different online stores and compare their offers, you will save both money and time!</item>
        <item>Browse supplies regularly\tMake sure to browse all your home food supplies regularly to avoid unnecessary past food, this both helps to limit wasted food and will help you save some money. Review your supplies for example weekly and move all items getting close to expiration date to the front of the shelves</item>
        <item>Buy a water filter\tInstead of buying bottled water it\'s worth investing in a water filter and reusable bottle with a built-in carbon filter</item>
        <item>Test cheap food\tDo not believe in the word that \"the brand is better\". Often, the same products are offered under the brand name supermarkets. Read ingredients, check if it\'s the same manufacturer, buy for test and decide yourself whether you satisfy the product for half the price without the logo.</item>
        <item>Change bank account for the one without fees\tBanks change their offer quite frequently, and we should react and change banks. Loyalty in this sector - does not pay.</item>
        <item>Close the unused bank accounts\tIf you have a account bank account that is unnecessary - close them because maybe you limit the possibility to take advantage of the promotion for new customers. Additionally when bank changes their fees, you won\'t be affected</item>
        <item>Use the bonus moneyback\tSome banks support your loyalty - make sure to check your bank offer. Heavy use of the services of the bank (transfer salaries, purchases with debit cards) give you the chance for bonuses of some banks. Earnings depend on the earnings and creativity.</item>
        <item>Repay the loans in other currencies using currency bought online\tInternet Exchange offices have a low spread (the difference between the buying and selling) so that you earn as much as 10 cents on every-selling 1 euro. This will make a lot of difference if you have a lot of loans</item>
        <item>Do not buy any investment products you do not understand.\tIt\'s really simple rule. A lot of people lose by investing in financial products, for example. Wrapped in insurance policies</item>
        <item>Consolidate debts.\tIt is not always possible, but it is worth trying. Even small decrease for a large debt can yield significant profits</item>
        <item>Automate payment for monthly services.\tFor services that you are subscribed to, like for example phone, try to automate monthly payments. This will save time and reduce the risk that something you forget.</item>
        <item>Check if you do not pay for unnecessary financial products.\tReview credit card statements and accounts and see what charges you have to pay every month.</item>
        <item>Cut the credit cards\tCredit cards can be helpful, but only to the point where there is over the debt (in particular repays the debt-to-date). In any other case I advise you to avoid cards because they give a false sense of holding money and are the easiest way to spend more that you can afford.</item>
        <item>Invest in employee savings plans.\tSome companies (usually large corporations) have pension plans for their employees, in which co-invest with the employee. Find out if your company is such a program and how you can maximize the benefits.</item>
        <item>Enjoy the privileges of the employee.\tGo to the HR department in your company and learn what you can expect: a grant of holidays, gifts for children, financial support in difficult situations, interest-free or low-interest loans, additional days of sick leave or holidays, scholarships, training. Many big companies have such programs. Loan from work can help pay off the debt on a credit card</item>
        <item>Actively look for discounts\tAsk for everything. You can get a discount by paying by credit card, you can have a cheaper (or price) home insurance, sometimes you will get discounts when paying using cash.</item>
        <item>Try to pay annually\tWhere possible try to pay annual fee instead of monthly, this will save you about 10–15%</item>
        <item>Plan trips and holidays in advance.\tWhether you spend on vacation a lot or a little. Planning ahead will save you a lot of money.</item>
        <item>Choose the optimal means of transportation\tChoose between bike, car, public transport or simply walking for your daily commute. Try to use each mean of transport for a month, and measure how much you spend</item>
        <item>Become a blood donor.\tThis might take you few years, but depending on country/city you might get a unlimited free public transport ticket or other privileges.</item>
        <item>Share a car to work\tIt is possible to cut your commute costs by sharing car with your work mates - investigate which ones of your colleagues live nearby and can share a car with you.</item>
        <item>Employ eco driving\tDriving economically can lead to significant fuel savings, depending on the car you have, this can save you up to 30%</item>
        <item>Do not break law when driving\tThe fines for speeding or illegal parking can result in two kinds of problems: you will have to pay them eventually and also you might loose a lot of time.</item>
        <item>Replace a car with a bike.\tTry to plan your daily commute, maybe on few days per week you can take a bike instead of a car?</item>
        <item>Keep the correct tire pressure in your car\tAccording to the experts the tire pressure directly translates into fuel consumption and scale of savings can reach up to 5%.</item>
        <item>Wash your car at the manual car wash.\tThis has several advantages: cheaper, you can do this yourself, and rarely goes to the car wash - your car will be cleaner than after automatic car wash.</item>
        <item>Replace your car for a more economical one.\tSome cars, especially older ones, can be very uneconomical, they will use a lot of fuel and maintenance costs can kill you. Sometimes you have to take a very drastic decision and consider buying a new car.</item>
        <item>Invest time in planning the purchase of the (new) car.\tEconomical and reliable car, combined with a large number of kilometers traveled can help you save tens of thousands of dollars during its lifetime.</item>
        <item>If you do not have a car, it is good think before you buy.\tConsider all aspects of buying a car, prepare a spreadsheet that will calculate all costs for you - if you buy the worng model, the fuel price might happen to be a very minor factor in the total cost during it\'s lifetime.</item>
        <item>Rent your apartment closer to work\tSave time, you won\'t have to weak up early and will save time on commute. Calculate if possibly paying higher rent will be worth. On the other hand, if you have a good connection, consider moving to cheaper apartments outside city</item>
        <item>Use nightly tariffs\tCount whether it will pay off. If you work long hours and during the day the apartment is empty, the nightly tariff will have a lower cost of electricity in the evening and night. Make sure that home appliances like washing machine, dishwasher, etc.. will work during that time</item>
        <item>Minimize the number of devices being in standby mode.\tSwitching off devices at home can lead to electricity savings. Make sure they don\'t go into standby but are completely unplugged.</item>
        <item>Avoid the use of unnecessary subscriptions.\tAdditional channels on cable TV, too large internet packages, subscriptions, etc… - all this can add up to high costs.</item>
        <item>Keep the refrigerator in order.\tIt is said that the fridge is responsible for 25% of energy consumption in homes. Make sure that it is properly set, and had good ventilation and it\'s not covered in dust.</item>
        <item>Change your mobile operator.\tThink not only about changing operator, but also the transition from subscription to prepaid or vice versa. Depending on your usage patterns this can save some money</item>
        <item>Turn off all unnecessary phone services.\tAnalyze the phone bill. Maybe you are paying for internet packages you don\'t use</item>
        <item>Search for cheaper or free entertainment.\tEspecially in the spring and summer you can participate in many free outdoor events, concerts, open air theater, events for kids, shows, etc..</item>
        <item>Use the library.\tEspecially if you have children. Library usually have not only books but also movies or audiobooks.</item>
        <item>Invite friends to your home instead of hanging out\tYou can save up to 50% of money, especially on the alcohol.</item>
        <item>Make your own gifts instead of buying stuff from the store.\tYou can make food mixes, candles, bread, cookies, soap, and all kinds of other things at home quite easily and inexpensively. These make spectacular gifts for others because they involve your homemade touch, plus quite often they’re consumable, meaning they don’t wind up filling someone’s closet with junk. Even better – include a personal handwritten note with the gift. This will make it even more special than anything you could possibly buy down at the mall, plus it saves you money.</item>
        <item>Master the thirty day rule.\tWhenever you’re considering making an unnecessary purchase, wait thirty days and then ask yourself if you still want that item. Quite often, you’ll find that the urge to buy has passed and you’ll have saved yourself some money by simply waiting. If you want, you can even keep a “thirty day list” where you write down the item and the day you’ll reconsider it, but I prefer just to keep this one in my head – that way, I often just forget about the unimportant things.</item>
        <item>If you have to buy gifts, then buy them throughout the year.\tAnd the best for clearance sales right after the previous festival, make sure you don\'t buy christmas gifts in December</item>
        <item>Avoid impulsive shopping.\tIf the purchase wasn\'t planned and it incurs significant cost, make sure you wait at least a week before making final decision.</item>
        <item>If you want something, enter it in the list of your gifts.\tDo not buy this yourself but share gift lists across friends, this will make more useful and cost effective gifts.</item>
        <item>Do not take your children shopping.\tIn particular, the supermarkets. There, marketing experts ensure that your child will be under their influence.</item>
        <item>Check prices on your smart phone during shopping.\tStand in front of a shelf in stores when buying more expensive items, check prices online and compare if ordering them online or somewhere else will be worth it.</item>
        <item>Do not treat shopping as a way of spending free time.\tDon\'t go shopping just to kill some time, you will have high chance of buying something you don\'t like or want.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
