<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Money Saving Tips</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_details">Tip</string>
    <string name="previous">&lt;&lt;</string>
    <string name="next">&gt;&gt;</string>
    <string name="random">Random</string>

    <string-array name="tips">
        <item>item pierwszy\tasdfwwwwwwwwwwwwwwwwww\n\n\n\n\n\nwwwwwwwwwwwwwwwww\n\n\nwww\n\n\www\n\n\n\n\nwwwwww</item>
        <item>Switch your bank accounts to a bank that respects you\tYou shouldn’t be spending your hard-earned money on maintenance fees – you also should be earning some serious interest on your checking and savings accounts. Interest rates are not what they once were, but some of the best free checking accounts and best savings accounts can be found online</item>
        <item>Turn off the television\tOne big way to save money is to watch less television. There are a lot of financial benefits to this: less exposure to guilt-inducing ads, more time to focus on other things in life, less electrical use, and so on. It’s great to unwind in the evening, but seek another hobby to do that.</item>
        <item>Turn a critical eye to your "collections"\tMost people collect something – what do you collect? Is it something that consistently brings you joy?\nOr is it something that you just do out of habit at this point? Does the collection itself have value? Could you perhaps “trim the fat” from this collection by getting rid of duplicates or getting rid of the items you no longer use? Also, could you perhaps cut down on your spending on that hobby? Focus on trimming the things you don’t feel strongly about – if you dig into things that bother you, you’re going to eventually relapse.</item>
        <item>Make your own gifts instead of buying stuff from the store\tYou can make food mixes, candles, bread, cookies, soap, and all kinds of other things at home quite easily and inexpensively. These make spectacular gifts for others because they involve your homemade touch, plus quite often they’re consumable, meaning they don’t wind up filling someone’s closet with junk. Even better – include a personal handwritten note with the gift. This will make it even more special than anything you could possibly buy down at the mall, plus it saves you money.</item>
        <item>Master the thirty day rule\tWhenever you’re considering making an unnecessary purchase, wait thirty days and then ask yourself if you still want that item. Quite often, you’ll find that the urge to buy has passed and you’ll have saved yourself some money by simply waiting. If you want, you can even keep a “thirty day list” where you write down the item and the day you’ll reconsider it, but I prefer just to keep this one in my head – that way, I often just forget about the unimportant things.</item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>
        <item></item>

    </string-array>

</resources>
